roycewhitaker@rocketmail.com

ABOUT

Seasoned IT professional with 8 years of experience, specializing in automation and server management. Skilled in PowerShell, Python, Bash, and Microsoft technologies, with a proven record of mastering new tools rapidly. As a collaborative team player, I am eager to solve complex problems and drive innovation.

EDUCATION

B.S., Engineering Technology at San Jose State University

Spring 2022

Major: Computer Network Systems Management

Minor: Business Management

CERTS

CompTIA Network+
CompTIA A+

February 2024 April 2019

EXPERIENCE

Sutro Biopharma, San Carlos, CA

March 2023 - Present

- Desktop Support Specialist
 - Troubleshoot and triage service requests via face to face and/or remote access
 - Work independently to ensure timely resolution of tickets
 - Perform the creation & ongoing maintenance of SharePoint sites
 - Secure SharePoint sites using industry best-practices and moving permission controls to Azure AD/On-prem AD security groups
 - Manage hardware assets & software licensing of user computers
 - Develop scripts and automations to provision user computers
 - Integrate apps into an MDM (VMWare Workspace One/Intune) to facilitate silent app installations
 - Support PC Refresh Program: replacing old computers with new computers; data and settings migration from old computers to new computers
 - Create IT documentation for IT staff and user guides to reduce repetitive tickets

Contract Desktop Support Specialist

March 2022 - March 2023

- Provide direct customer service to a cross-section of users
- Investigate a wide variety of issues and recommend solutions
- Provide Tier 1 technical support to the QC labs and MFG suites in a GxP environment.
- Perform computer upgrades and installs
- Support diverse systems: iPhone, data backups, Microsoft Office 365 on Windows & Mac systems, Microsoft Active Directory, Microsoft Exchange mail server, and antivirus software
- Assist with Windows patch management and security updates of user + lab machines
- Troubleshooting, resolving, and identifying root causes
- Perform user, lab, and GMP software installations

Assistant System Administrator

- Troubleshoot Microsoft Office 365 and Active Directory
- Maintain company infrastructure: domain, thin clients, and servers. Including routers & switches
- Manage Microsoft Active Directory & network folders
- Troubleshoot business-critical machines and devices running everything from Win. XP to CentOS
- Support in-production Printers, Microscopes, Cameras, Drill Machines, Lamination Machines, Engineering Machines, and thin clients.
- Perform remote support with ConnectWise Control, VNC, & TeamViewer

San Jose State University, San Jose, CA

September 2017 - March 2022

- Senior IT Support Specialist
 - Provide IT support to 200+ employees & students
 - Conduct maintenance and repairs on a wide array of computers in an enterprise environment
 - Maintain Microsoft Active Directory & network folders
 - Secure critical local web services used to manage work orders and company assets

PROJECT Network Share to SharePoint Migration

February 2023 – April 2024

Sutro Biopharma, San Carlos, CA

Goal: Move department file shares onto SharePoint to improve collaboration, security, and accessibility of documents

Strategy: Scan department folders for optimal files (Office documents & PDFs). Work with departments directly to decide what can be archived, what needs to stay on the network share, and which files would be best served from SharePoint

- Queue tasks for migration agents to perform as resources become available
- Verify integrity of moved files and restrict access to the source directories
- Architect security groups and settings to allow for collaboration where possible while also observing the principle of least privilege and confidentiality

RELEVANT COURSES	Programming Concepts Networking Theory & Application	Cloud Computing Network Administration	Connected Products Cyber Security
SKILLS	Ticketing Connectwise Zendesk	Cloud Azure Office 365 Linux Server/Desktop	Programming Python JavaScript PowerShell
	Tools Active Directory VMWare ESX & vCenter	MDM VMware Workspace One Intune Zoom	Microsoft Windows Server Azure Active Directory SharePoint Online